Polisar, Eric Papers /3035
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Government statistics on the labor market and minorities, other civil rights material (Box 17)
  - US Civil Rights Commission and Southern School Desegregation, 1964-1967 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - White House Conference "To Fulfill These Rights", 1966 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - US Conference of Mayors - Changing Employment Practices in Constitution Industry, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - US Dept. of Labor - Policy and Program Seminars, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Negros in the US: Their Economic and Social Situation, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    US Dept. of Labor
  - Labor and the New Urban Society (Box 17, Folder 50)
    US Dept. of Labor Bureau of Labor Statistics
  - Sub-Employment in the Slums of NY, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    Surveys by US Dept. of Labor
- Various publications by other ILR Professors; other publications and committee meetings and reports. (Box 18)
  - Work Stoppages and Teachers: History and Project, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Hildebrand - Collective Bargaining in the Public Sector, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Brockman - Impasses Resolution Procedure, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Hildebrand - National Academy of Arbitrations, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - McKelvey - Role of State Agencies in Public Employee Labor Relations, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Belasco - Resolving Dispute over Contract Terms, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Gross and the Public Service Training Program on Collective Bargaining, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Hanslowe - Resolution on Impasses in Teacher Negotiations, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hanslowe - Labor Relations in Public Employment, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Hanslowe - Labor Relations in Public Employment, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Macy-Federal Employee-Management Cooperation Program: A review, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Polisar-Employees and the Right to Strike and Correspondence, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Lieberman-NYC Welfare Strike and Aftermath, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - NY Seminar on Labor Relations in State Government, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    A list of participants in the Seminar
  - Schwulst-Temporary Commission on NYC Finances, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Rottmann-The Postal Experience, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Hanslowe, Helmcke, and Polisar-Plainview Federation of Teachers, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Hoffman-Which Bargaining Agent for Teachers?, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Bloom-UFT and Problem of Integration and Quality Education, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Kaye - AFSCME vs. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Ross-Case Study of Auburn Police Benevolent or How to Play Boy Labor Consultant, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Wechsler, The Association in Transition, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Lefkowitz-Do Public Employees have a Right to Strike?, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Conference On: Employee-Management Relations in Public Service, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - IRRA - Collective Bargaining in Public Service, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    Proceedings of the 1966 Annual Spring Meeting
  - AFRSCME Washington Convention, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - NYS Department of Mental Hygiene, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Public Employees and the Right to Strike, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - The Public Personnel Administration-Eastern Regional Conference, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Mayors Conference-"Trends in Public Employee Relations, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Wurf Speech-Conference of Mayors, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Donovan-ILR Report Card for Social Science Teachers, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Commentary on Federal Labor-Management Relations Policy, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Includes state reports (Box 19)
  - State Reports on Laws, 1965-1967 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Laws in Massachusetts, Connecticut, Wisconsin, and Michigan
  - Report on Connecticut Municipal Employee Bargaining, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut Commission Report, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Michigan Report, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Review of a Year's Experience in Michigan Schools, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Collective Bargaining in State Employment, Oregon's Experience, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Riesel-Inside Labor Rocky Road for Rockefeller, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Illinois Governor's Advisory Commission on Labor-Management Policy for Public Employees, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - NYS Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Washington Report, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - AFT Seminar, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - New Careers Development Center, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The American Federalist-Official Monthly Magazine, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration News, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Industrial Bulletin, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Union Democracy in Action, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - The Changing Employment Relationship in Public Schools, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Doherty: Employer-Employee Relations in the Public Schools, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Hanslowe: Emerging Law of Labor Relations in Public Employment, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Report of Task Force on State and Local Gov't Labor Relations, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - The Labor Elite: Is it Revolutionary?, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    By Henry A. Landsberger
  - Institute of Pubic Administration, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Negroes In Apprenticeship, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Policies and Priorities for Progress: The Economy in 1967 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Employee-Management Relations in the Public Service, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Hildebrand-Poverty, Income Maintenance, and the Negative Income Tax, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Arms and Police Protection - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Hospital Strike and Nurses Salaries, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Public Employment-Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Sanitation Strike in NYC-Newspaper Clippings, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - The Taylor Law-Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Teacher's Strike: Florida, Pittsburgh, and Washington, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    Newspaper Clippings
  - Teacher's Strike-Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Transportation Strikes: Buses, railroads, taxis, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Welfare - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Civil Rights-Washington's Opinions and Panels, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Civil Rights-Newspaper Clippings, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Civil Right-Education, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Civil Rights-Housing, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    Newspapers Clippings
  - Civil Rights-Jobs-Newspaper Clippings, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Civil Rights-Rioting-Newspaper Clippings, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    News Clippings from Carolina and New Jersey
  - Welfare and Anti-Poverty-Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Civil Rights- Police Weapons for Riots, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Polisar Research Topics and Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 44)
- Polisar mss. And reports. AFL-CIO Civil Rights file; EEOC Material; BLS Social and Economic Conditions of Negroes in the US (Box 20)
  - Polisar Research Topics and Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Vital Speeches of the Day, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - NAACP Convention - Workshop on Discrimination in Employment, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Collective Bargaining in the Public Sector: An Analytical View by Hildebrand, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - A Summary of Collective Bargaining Law in Public Employment (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Statement to NYS Advisory Committee to US Commission of Civil Rights, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Raskin - The NYC Newspaper Strike, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Max Way - Labor Unions Are Worth the Price, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Changing Patterns of Work and Workers and Population Dynamics (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - The Role of the State Agencies in Public Employee Labor Relations, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Conference on Employee-Management Relations in the Public Service, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - AFL-CIO Civil Rights, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - EEOC Budget and Organization, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - EEOC Technical Assistance Contract, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - EEOC 1st Annual Report, 1966-1968 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - EEOC Technical Assistance Division - Memos, Interviews, and EEOC investigations., 1967 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - EEOC Technical Assistance Division-Memos, and interviews, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - EEOC-Technical Assistance Division Reports, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - EEOC Interim Report - Textile Program, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Robertson, Regional Office Operations, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Conciliations Office Report, 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - EEOC Fiscal Year Contract, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - EEOC Structure- Potomac Institute Report (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - OFCC Report- Construction, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Bias in the Building Industry Report, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - EEOC- Meeting with Regional Director, Atlanta Office, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Nap Johnson - The Outlook for Labor, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - EEOC- Polisar Research Polisar, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Technical Assistance-New Plant Program, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Technical Assistance - Labor Program, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - EEOC Research- Survey Textiles, Carolinas, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - EEOC Research- Osburn Report, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Technical Assistance on Textiles, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - EEOC Tenure of Commissioners - Senior Staff, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - EEOC - Wayne State Conference "Promise vs. Performance", 1967 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - EEOC- Research Inventory in EEO, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - EEO Research - Economic Status of Negro Worker, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - EEOC Research - EEOC Document and Reference Text, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - EEOC Research - Employment Opportunities Contract Construction, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - EEOC Research - White Collar Employment Opportunities for Minorities, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - EEOC Research Invitees Meeting, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - EEOC-Guidelines on Employment Testing Problems, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - EEOC Research Reports, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - EEOC External Research Projects, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Ferman- Negro and Equal and Employment Opportunities, A Review of 20 companies, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 45)
- AFL-CIO Civil Rights file; EEOC Material; BLS Social and Economic Conditions of Negroes in the US. General Office Files. Conferences and meeting files (Box 21)
  - Marshall-Negro Participation in Apprenticeship Programs, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO Civil Rights Committee - Membership, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Operating Engineers - Apprentice Recruiting, Baltimore, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - EEOC - IBEW, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Building Trades Legislation Conf. Washington, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - EEOC Field Circulars and Manual, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - US Dept. of Labor - Area Trends in Employment and Unemployment, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - EEOC - Shulman Speech, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Blumrosen Speech on Employment Discrimination, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Blumrosen - Article and Sovern Book Review, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - EEOC Research- Nine City Minority Groups, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - BLS-Social and Economic Conditions of Negroes in the US, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - National Institute of Labor Education-List of Committees and Members (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Panama Canal Company/Canal Zone Government Personnel Bureau, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Public Personnel Association, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Proposal for a Non-Residential Program (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - International Conference of Commissions For Human Rights, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Union Democracy In Action, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Vietnam Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - The Many Faces of Poverty, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - American Arbitration Association Pamphlets and Articles, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - The American Association od University Women, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - C.B.S. Television, 1965-1967 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Civil Service Employees Assoc. - 55 Years of Progress, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Institute of International Education (IIE), 1965 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - IRRA Newsletter, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - IRRA Equal Employment Opportunities, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - NBC Company Equal Employment Opportunity, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Nile Automation Project, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Project in Labor- Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Unions and Organized Labor-Miscellaneous, 1963-1967 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Young Socialist League, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - NYS Employees' Retirement System, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Insurance, Medicare, and Social Security, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Labor Management Institute - Labor Arbitration Panel, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Atlantic Labor Press Conference, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Buffalo AFL-CIO Council Conf., 1962 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Building Service Employees On-Campus Conference, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Civil Service Employees Assoc.-Staff Training, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Development in Public Service Labor Relations, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Eastern Region Public Personnel Association, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Employee-Management Relations in the Public Service Conference, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    Includes a map of Ithaca
  - Report on Employee-Management Relations Conference by G. Brooks, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Employee-Management Relations in Local Government, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Hiring, Developing, and Promoting Negro Employees, 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - First I.C.F.T.U. World Conference on Education in the Labor Movement, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    International Confederation of Free Trade Unions ( I.C.F.T.U.)
  - IRRA 20th Annual Meeting, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Invitational Conference of Labor Educators, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Labor and the Defense Economy, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 50)
- Conferences and meeting files. Pamphlets from AFSCME convention (1968); education and research guide; fact finding panel for advisory arbitration; City of NY and Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Unions, Vol. 1-7 (2/6/65) (Box 22)
  - Speech on Disarmament by Dr. Hans Bethe (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Nairo Conference: The Law and Equal Employment, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - NYS Public Employment Labor Relations Conference, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Public Services International Congress, 1967-1968 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - National University Extension Association, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Public Personnel Association, 1966-1967 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Root Problems of Public Employees: An Interview, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The Union Leader as a Decision Maker, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Includes drafts of document
  - United Steelworkers of America, District 4, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - United Steelworkers, District 4, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Urban Issues Affecting Labor at State Constitutional Convention, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - AFSCME-17th International Convention, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Includes other AFSCME affiliated documents
  - Collective Bargaining Procedures in Public Employment, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - AFSCME Organizers Manual (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.1, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol. 1
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.2, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.2
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.3, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.3
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.4, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.4
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.5, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.5
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.6, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.6
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employee Union Vol.7, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.7
  - Education and Research Guide Vol. 1, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Education and Research Guide Vol.2, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 23)
- Fact finding panel for advisory arbitration; City of NY and Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Unions, Vol 7-13 (2/6/65) (Box 23)
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.7-8, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.7-8
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.9, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.9
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.9 cont., 1965 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.9 cont.
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.10, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Fact Finding Panel Vpl.10
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.10-11, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.10-11
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.12, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.12
  - Welfare Employees Local 371 and Social Service Employees Union Vol.13, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Fact Finding Panel Vol.13
  - Drafts of Personal Statement by Chairman Dean Schottland, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Advisory Fact Finding and Arbitration Panel